<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alexander Gibson</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Alexander Gibson</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Eight Books That Have Changed Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/books/</guid>
      <description>The Greek philosopher Zeno was given the advice; “to live the best life, you should have conversations with the dead”. Books facilitate these conversations. Many of my best ideas and personal philosophies have come directly from such conversations. The following is a non-exhaustive list of a few books that have shaped me in recent years, that you may find of interest. 1.&#x9;War Doctor: Surgery On The Front Line – David Nott&#xD;While my interest in medicine came from a documentary I saw in 2018, this is the book that I keep coming back to.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Better Life Without Social Media</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/social/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/social/</guid>
      <description>For most of my adult life, friends and I have talked about the addictive and negative aspects of social media. A constant highlight reel with individualised targeted ads, an algorithm designed to maximise engagement, not to mention infinite scrolling. Previously, having tried removing social media sporadically with little luck, I’ve now permanently deleted Instagram, Snapchat, Reddit, TikTok, X and deactivated my Facebook account.&#xA;For a week back in December, I aimed to spend as little time on my phone as possible and managed less than one hour a day.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimism in Meta-Research</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/meta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/meta/</guid>
      <description>I got to experience my first insight of ‘meta-research’ at the 2023 AIMOS conference. Before this, I had almost no knowledge about meta-research. It sparked an interest in me for integrity and good research practices. Often meta-research can appear pessimistic or cynical of broader research, showcasing the flaws and faults, which made it refreshing to see a dedicated session for ‘some good news’ at AIMOS 2024. Four talks presented by David Mellor, Tammy Hoffman, Ivan Oransky and Anita Bandrowski gave light to the progress and positive effects meta-research and open science is having on the wider research.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Took 9565mg of Caffeine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/caffeine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/caffeine/</guid>
      <description>At the end of my MPhil, I had completed a great deal of work. But I was left wondering some stats… How many hours did I put into this? How many words did I write? How many words did I read? Or how much caffeine did I consume?&#xA;Given I was continuing with a PhD I thought it will be easy enough to track my coffee consumption. And that’s exactly what I’ve been doing for the last three months.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 13:38:41 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/contact/</guid>
      <description>** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder.&#xA;Formspree requires a (free) account and new form to be set up. The link is made on the final published url in the field: Restrict to Domain. It is possible to register up to 2 emails free and you can select which one you want the forms to go to within Formspree in the Settings tab.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contributors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/contributors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/contributors/</guid>
      <description>Thank you to all the folks who have contributed both technical and creative skills to this project:&#xA;Desirée De Leon &amp;#x1f992; (designed 5 of the custom color themes, made illustrations for the workshop, and provided general aesthetic feedback along the way)&#xA;Garrick Aden-Buie &amp;#x1f9d9; (debugged headroom.js and lent his panelset.js code to the theme)&#xA;Allison Horst &amp;#x1f415; (awesome illustrations of campfires, seedlings, and evergreens, as well as my R Markdown hedgehog mascot &amp;#x1f994;)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/license/</guid>
      <description>My blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
