<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Curiosity Chronicles on Alexander Gibson</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Curiosity Chronicles on Alexander Gibson</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Optimism in Meta-Research</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/meta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/meta/</guid>
      <description>I got to experience my first insight of ‘meta-research’ at the 2023 AIMOS conference. Before this, I had almost no knowledge about meta-research. It sparked an interest in me for integrity and good research practices. Often meta-research can appear pessimistic or cynical of broader research, showcasing the flaws and faults, making it nice to see a dedicated session for ‘some good news’ at AIMOS 2024. Four talks presented by David Mellor, Tammy Hoffman, Ivan Oransky and Anita Brandrowski gave light to the progress and positive affects meta-research and open science is having on wider research, policy and change.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Took 9565mg of Caffeine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/blog/caffeine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/blog/caffeine/</guid>
      <description>At the end of my MPhil, I had completed a great deal of work. But I was left wondering some stats… How many hours did I put into this? How many words did I write? How many words did I read? Or how much caffeine did I consume?&#xA;Given I was continuing with a PhD I thought it will be easy enough to track my coffee consumption. And that’s exactly what I’ve been doing for the last three months.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
